Hello everyone, in this tutorial video, we will learn about some adjustments we need to make to virtual models before we really start making clothes.
First of all, in our software, if you want to use a virtual model, you can import this virtual model in the form of FBX or OBJ.
Here we import a FBX file.
After importing the FBX file, there are some options at the bottom.
The first option is the object you imported, and the second option is the proportion you imported.
The proportion is actually the unit of the imported object.
Everyone must pay attention to the units.
For example, here I imported a relatively small unit when I imported the model and imported it as mm.
Because the default input unit of our software is mm.
After importing, compare the ground network grid.
This is the ground network grid.
This model is relatively small.
Because the units we import into the model are relatively small,
some of the default settings in the software, including surface rigidity, rendering thickness, and collision thickness,
their basic units are mm.
In this case, if we use this model to create a version,
then if we open the grid display here, you will see that its grid number is actually very small.
In this case,
we can't make a version on it.
Because its grid number is too small.
The reason why the grid number is small is because our default particle diameter is 20 mm.
That is to say, one edge of a grid is 20 mm.
If we forcefully reduce its particle diameter for this model,
even if it is reduced to 5,
because now one edge is still 5 mm,
its transition is still not smooth enough.
And when we put the version on this virtual model,
because the virtual model is imported,
its surface rigidity is default set to 3 mm.
Therefore, compared to the size of this version,
it seems that this air thickness is particularly thick.
Therefore, after we import a model,
we must make sure that its ratio is correct.
Next, let's take a look at what happens if we choose a larger ratio.
Compared to the ground network grid, we can see that
the ground network grid is significantly higher than the ground network grid after its arms are opened.
If it is a normal proportion model,
its arms are not higher than the ground network grid.
Then we can see that if we rely on the modeling of the model to draw the version,
this version will be a larger version.
Therefore, even if the particle diameter is 20 mm,
its network grid is also a lot.
If we start the simulation to simulate this version,
the computer will run very slowly.
If you are not sure what the unit of the model you want to import is,
you can open the virtual model you brought in our software,
and then use this virtual model as reference,
and then choose its unit.
After importing HANA,
you will find that this model is much larger compared to HANA.
That means that when we choose a unit,
we have to choose a unit that is one level smaller than this unit.
Now, after determining the unit,
we can import the model first.
Because we originally chose millimeters and inches,
here we choose a centimeter.
In addition to importing units,
we also have a proportion when importing.
If you need to do a certain reduction of this proportion because of your own settings,
it is also possible.
After importing the virtual model,
if you import an FBX file,
it may not automatically generate the layout and layout points.
Now that we have talked about the layout and layout points,
let's take a look at some settings about the virtual model display.
First of all, the first one is to display the virtual model.
This is very simple.
It means to display all virtual models or hide all virtual models.
Then we can choose the display layout point and display layout board.
Here, because there is no layout point or layout board around the virtual model,
it will not be displayed.
After selecting display X-ray,
it will display the virtual model's own Google joint information.
After selecting a joint point,
we can rotate the layout or move the layout to rotate and move this Google.
If the FBX file with the layout is imported,
a prompt will pop up to remind you.
If you modify the joint point or the Google point,
the animation brought by this file will disappear.
Should we continue?
Yes.
Then we can rotate the layout or move the layout
to adjust the virtual model's posture after selecting the joint point.
When we select a joint point,
there is an option of symmetrical editing on the upper right of the layout.
If you click on it, it means that the symmetrical editing is opened.
After clicking on this button,
the layout will disappear.
Its moving option is only rotating,
and all rotating operations are symmetrical.
Of course, only in the original set layout,
the name of the initial set joint symmetry point is corresponding,
so that symmetrical editing can be carried out.
If your joint point can not be linked to the left and right together,
please first confirm in other software
whether your joint point is set to the name is corresponding to each other.
After selecting display virtual model size,
the size information on the virtual model will be displayed.
This size information is required for us to use the basic length measurement in advance,
or the basic circle measurement, etc.
The choice of virtual model measurement
will be displayed only after creating a measurement line.
For example, here,
when I create a virtual model measurement,
if I switch back to select the moving tool,
it will not be displayed,
unless I choose to display virtual model measurement information here.
The next option is to display the line virtual model.
If you want to display the line virtual model,
first we need to create the line virtual model.
After using the line virtual model tool,
click on the virtual model and create a point.
During the process,
press the Ctrl key to create a curve point.
When we use the line virtual model,
this shape created becomes a closed shape,
use the flattening tool to select this closed shape,
then press the Enter key to remove the sheet.
The removed sheet can be used as a basic sheet,
and be modified above.
If we want to adjust these lines,
we can use the edit line virtual model tool
to adjust its point or straight line.
Double-click on a point to select the entire shape,
press the Delete key to delete the entire shape.
In the default situation,
we use other tools that can't see the line virtual model.
The next one is to display the virtual model.
The default virtual model does not have a virtual model information,
and the virtual model information is that
we can use the virtual model information of different virtual models
to automatically adapt or automate the sheet.
In the 3D tool bar,
after selecting to create a point,
if there is a sheet in your 3D space,
it will remind you whether the file is not yet saved.
Remember to save it here.
Then we can start to measure the size of the virtual models
to create a point.
When creating a point,
you can use the information chart of this point
to draw the virtual model
based on its high position.
This is the same as the virtual model measurement.
Click, click, click,
and then click three points to determine a circle line.
First is the top view,
then the bottom view,
then the waist,
and then step by step to create a point.
During the creation process,
press the Shift key
to create those points along the level or value direction.
When you have created all the measurements,
click on the application,
the virtual model will be worn on the virtual model,
just like what I drew.
We will see that the virtual model
is actually a particularly tight deep red color,
so we will use the dark red clothing information.
Through the virtual model table,
this layer of red clothing information,
we can achieve different body shapes
of the virtual model's clothing accessories.
If you want to delete a piece of information,
select this information,
then press the Delete key
to rewrite this part of the information.
In other words,
you can re-create the measurement.
After the modification,
you need to click on the application again
to apply the clothing.
If your model is not symmetrical on the left and right,
here we can cancel the selection of its symmetry.
If you click on the application,
you will find that there is a small difference.
We can manually drag it
to make the whole dress more flat.
Finally, remember to save this virtual model
to allow the virtual model to have the dress information.
After that,
we will look at another
menu bar related to virtual models.
Here we can change the virtual model
to black and white surface or grid display.
Another point is that
all the models that are imported to our software,
its grid type
will eventually be automatically adjusted
to a triangular grid.
That's it for some basic knowledge
about import.